[ Cheering ]
[欢呼]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Welcome to Making Great
&gt;&gt; 欢迎来到
SiriKit Experiences.
“SiriKit 酷炫体验”发布会
My name is Jose Angel Castillo
我是 Jose Angel Castillo Sanchez
Sanchez and with my coworker
我将与我的合作者
Rohit [assumed spelling], we
Rohit [按照发音拼写] 一起
want to tell you all about it.
来给大家详细讲解
It has been a year since we
一年前
announced SiriKit.
我们发布了 SiriKit
Since then, many applications
从那以后 许多应用都
have [inaudible].
开始 [音质不清晰]
We have heard your feedback, the
我们收到了大家的反馈
developers feedback.
来自开发者的反馈
With that, we have put together
根据这些反馈 我们把问题汇总为
four major areas that we want to
四大类别 今天我们就想
focus on today.
逐个重点讲解
First, we want to talk about
首先 我们想谈谈
contact resolution.
联系人解析的问题
If your application is a
如果你的应用
messaging, call, or a payments
是短信 呼叫或者支付类应用
application, you probably have
你可能已经
dealed [phonetic] with it.
使用过它了
After that, we're going to talk
在这个问题之后 我们想谈谈
about security.
安全性问题
If your application requires an
如果你的应用要求
authorization to finalize a
授权过后才能完成交易
transaction, we'll tell you how
我们将告诉你
to achieve that in simple steps.
如何通过几个简单步骤来实现它
Next, we're going to cover
然后 我们会谈一谈
custom vocabulary.
自定义词汇
Siri understands many words in
Siri 词汇量很大
many languages, but there might
而且懂多门语言
be some specific words to your
但你的应用可能会遇到某些特定词汇
application you might want to
你可能想要
tell Siri about.
让 Siri 了解清楚
Last but not least, we're going
最后同样重要的是 我们将
to cover UI testing.
谈到用户界面测试
Since the last year, we have
自去年以来 我们已经
made great improvement of how to
在 Siri 测试自动化方面
automate Siri testing.
取得了很大进步
Let's get started with contact
我们从联系人解析
resolution.
开始讲起吧
For this, I want to use a
关于这一点 我想
messaging example.
举一个短信发送的例子
A messaging application.
有一个短信应用
You may be familiar with it.
大家可能都很熟悉
UnicornChat.
叫 UnicornChat
For this, we're going to walk
为此 我们要
through the process of sending a
把发送信息的整个过程
message.
都演示一遍
Text hello to John on
在 UnicornChat 上
UnicornChat.
给 John 发送“你好”
We clearly see that John is who
我们很清楚
we want to message to.
John 是我们要发送消息的对象
In this case, on my address book
在这种情况下 我的通讯录里
I have multiple Johns.
有好几个 John
I have John Appleseed and John
有 John Appleseed
Baily.
还有 John Baily
From the user intent, it's not
而仅仅通过用户意图
yet clear which of these John I
想给哪个 John 发消息
want to message to.
这一点并不明确
In iOS 10.3, we introduced a new
在 iOS 10.3 中 我们曾经在
property in the INPerson object.
INPerson 对象中增加过一个新属性
SiriMatches.
就是 SiriMatches
SiriMatches is what Siri
SiriMatches 是 Siri
understands.
所理解的内容
In this case, the multiple
在这个例子中 指的就是这几个
Johns.
John
It can also be homophones to
也可能是 John 的
John.
同音异形字
You will get an array of
你将会得出一系列的
INPerson objects representing
INPerson 对象
all the possibilities that Siri
它们代表着 Siri 所理解的
understood.
所有可能性
Let's walk through the flow of
我们来演示一遍整个流程
text hello to John on
看看怎样在 UnicornChat 上
UnicornChat and see how we can
给 John 短信发送“你好”
take advantage of these
看看怎样利用这些
siriMatches to resolve our
SiriMatches 来解决
contact.
我们的联系人问题
Text John hello on UnicornChat.
在 UnicornChat 上给 John 发送“你好”
Siri clearly understands that
Siri 显然理解了
you want to text John.
你想要给 John 发消息
After that, Siri is going to
随后 Siri 将
contact your app extension or
联系你的 app extension
your intent parameter
或是你的 intent 参数
resolveRecipients.
resolveRecipients
In there, Siri is going to
在这一步 Siri 会给你
provide you an array of INPerson
提供一系列 INPerson 对象
objects, in this case, John
在这里 就是
Appleseed and John Baily.
John Appleseed 和 John Baily
As we saw earlier, John
我们之前已经看到过
part of my address book.
出现在我的通讯录里
It could also be they could be
它们也有可能是
part of my custom vocabulary on
我自定义词汇的一部分
my property address book on my
是我这个应用的通讯录属性
application.
内容
At this point, the
在这个时候
resolveRecipients intent
resolveRecipients intent 参数
parameter is going to get
将被调用
invoked and it's up to the app
然后由 app extension
extension to make a decision.
作出决定
Do we have enough information to
我们是否有足够的信息来
decide which John we want to
判断我们想要给哪个 John
send the message or do we need
发送消息 或者说 我们是否需要
the help from the user to decide
用户来帮助我们决定
which of these John?
是哪一个 John
In this case, we want to
在这种情况下 我们想
disambiguate.
消除歧义
We are going to return back to
我们将
Siri the disambiguation list.
把这个歧义消除匹配的列表返回给 Siri
The list is going to be John
列表将包括
Appleseed and John Baily.
John Appleseed 和 John Baily
Siri is going to bring a great
接下来 Siri 将为我们的用户
experience to our user, going to
带来非凡体验 它会询问
ask which one.
要找哪一个 John
John Baily or John Appleseed?
John Baily 还是 John Appleseed
At this point, it's up to the
这时 就要由
user to decide which John they
用户来决定哪一个 John
want to use on their message.
是他们想要发送消息的对象了
For the purpose of this flow,
在这个流程展示中
let's assume John Baily was the
假设 John Baily 是
one we chose.
我们的选择对象
Siri clearly understands that
Siri 清楚地理解到
John Baily is the message-- is
John Baily 是我们想发送消息
the contact we want to use.
想使用的联系人
Siri's going to provide back to
Siri 会反馈给
your resolveRecipients intent
你的 resolveRecipients intent
parameter that John Baily is the
参数 表明 John Baily
chosen INPerson object.
是被选中的 INPerson 对象
At this point, it's clearly that
这时候  情况就很清楚了
we want to message John Baily
我们想发送消息给 John Baily
and your intent recipients--
而你的 intent 接收者
intent parameter is ready to
intent 参数也已经准备要
move to the next stage.
要进入下一阶段了
To recap, we walked through the
概述而言 我们演示经历了
process when we have multiple
这样一番过程  当我们发现有好几个名字是
Johns on our address book and we
John 的人存在于通讯录里的过程
walked through the flow to
以及我们
disambiguate between them.
如何消除歧义的流程
We decided that we want to
我们决定想要
message John Baily.
发消息给 John Baily
But what if-- what if John Baily
可是如果如果 John Baily
has multiple phone numbers or
有多个电话号码或
email addresses or a combination
多个电邮地址 抑或是这两种情况
of both?
都存在呢
It is yet not clear that-- which
我们仍然不太明确
of these handles we want to use
究竟想要使用哪种方式
to send our message.
来发送消息
So, let's take a step back to
所以 我们往回再看一下
the point where the user chose
回到用户选择 John Baily 时
John Baily.
的状态
Siri understands that we want to
Siri 明白我们想要
message John Baily.
发消息给 John Baily
Siri's going to communicate back
Siri 将转而使用 “John Baily”
to your extension under
来联系你在
resolveRecipients intent
resolveRecipients intent 之下的
parameter with John Baily.
extension 参数
At this point, it's up to your
这时候 就需要通过你的
resolveRecipients intent
resolveRecipients intent
parameter implementation to
参数执行
access your address book and
来连接你的通讯录
make sure that you have enough
并确保你有足够信息
information to which one handle
来确定将要使用
is going to be used.
哪种联系方式
In this case, as we saw, we have
正如我们所见 在这种情况下 我们有
multiple handles, so we need
多个联系方式 所以需要
user input.
用户输入
Focusing on the phone handles,
如果问题集中到电话联系方式上
we're going to provide the
我们将向 Siri 提供
disambiguation list as we did
一个消除歧义列表
before with the multiple Johns,
就像我们之前处理多个 John 的情况一样
but in this case it's the
但这次是
multiple phone number handles.
多个电话号码联系方式
As we saw, we have home, mobile,
我们已经看到 这里有住宅电话 手机
and work.
还有工作电话
Siri is going to bring up a
Siri 将向用户发出
prompt to the user.
一个提示
Which one do you want to use?
“您想使用哪个号码”
So, in this case, it's pretty
所以 在这种情况下
clear to the user that they need
用户就很清楚自己需要
to pick one handle to send their
选择一个号码来发送
message.
消息
Let's assume the user wants to
我们假设用户想要
send to the mobile number.
发送消息到这个手机号
User says mobile to Siri.
用户对 Siri 说“手机”
We go through the same cycle
我们又会经历同样的循环过程
where Siri understands that you
Siri 明白
want to message on the mobile
你想要给 John Baily 的手机
number to John Baily.
号码发送消息
Siri's going to share that
Siri 会把这个信息
information back to the
发回给
resolveRecipients intent
resolveRecipients intent
parameter.
参数
Here you're going to get the
这样你将得到
whole information.
完整的信息
We want to message John Baily
我们想要发消息给 John Baily
and we want to do it in the
而且是想发送给他的
mobile handle.
手机号码
At this point, the
在这个时候
resolveRecipients intent
resolveRecipients intent
parameter returns success, so we
参数返回值为“成功”
have finalized picking our
于是我们就完成了
recipient and we can move on to
选择消息接收者的步骤 可以继续
the next stage.
下一步骤了
As we know, any SiriKit intent
我们知道 执行任何一个 SiriKit intent
implementation has three steps:
都有三个步骤：
resolve, confirm, and handle.
解析 确认和处理
So, let's take a look at sample
那么 让我们来看看
code of the resolveRecipients
resolveRecipients
intent parameter implementation.
intent 参数执行时的示例代码
Here I have resolveRecipients
现在我要执行
implemented.
resolveRecipients
The first thing that we're going
我们要做的第一件事
to do is make sure a recipient
就是确保
was provided.
已经有确定的接收者
In the case that the recipient
如果没有提供接收者
wasn't provided, we can
我们基本上可以要求 Siri
basically ask Siri to ask for
去向用户询问这个值的内容
that value to the user and we do
我们实现这一点的方法
that by returning needsValue.
是返回 needsValue
Siri will prompt the user.
这样 Siri 就会提示用户
To who do you want to send your
“您想向谁发送
message?
消息”
In the sample we walked through,
在我们刚刚演示过的例子里
the user said they want to
用户表示他们想要
message John.
给 John 发消息
So, we got John.
所以 我们得到的回复是 John
We got John Appleseed and John
我们已经有了 John Appleseed 和
Baily.
John Baily
Here is where we're going to
从这一步开始 我们要
resolve which of these
解析出
recipients we want to use or
我们想使用哪位接收者
provide the disambiguation list
或者将消除歧义列表
back to Siri so it can prompt to
返回给 Siri 让它来提示
the user.
用户
In the case that we need to
在我们需要向 Siri
provide back a list to Siri, we
提供一份列表的情况下
basically return that under a
我们基本上是在
completion handle.
结束句柄下予以返回的
Let's see a demo of this in
我们来演示一下
action.
这个操作过程
Here I have my resolveRecipients
现在我在 UnicornChat
intent parameter to be
应用上执行
implemented on my UnicornChat
我的 resolveRecipients
application.
intent 参数
As we saw, the first thing that
正如我们所看到的 我们需要做的
we need to do is to validate
第一件事 是确认
that we got a recipient.
我们有一位接收者
Here we're making sure that a
现在我们来确定
recipient got provided.
接收者是否已被提供
In the case the recipient wasn't
如果没有提供接收者
provided, we ask Siri to ask the
我们就要求 Siri
user that we need that value.
向用户询问我们需要这个值
Once we got that recipient
一旦我们已经获得了接收者
provided, we're going to process
我们就要继续对这些接收者
those recipients.
进行处理
Here we're going to walk through
现在 我们要浏览一遍
all the recipients that we got
Siri 提供的所有接收者
from Siri so we can process one
这样就可以逐个进行
by one.
处理
The first thing that I'm going
我要做的第一件事
to do, I'm going to check with
就是要查看
my address book to resolve this
我的通讯录 以便分析这位
recipient.
接收者
My address book will do the
我的通讯录将承担
heavy lifting to making sure
最棘手的问题 就是要确保
that we have a contact backing
我们有一个联系人
up that recipient.
与那位接收者能对上号
Once that's done, we need to
一旦这一步完成 我们就需要
make a decision.
做一个决定
The first case is where there's
第一种情况是
not a contact backing up that
没有哪位联系人能跟
recipient.
那位接收者对上号
Going back to our example of
回到我们刚讲的 John 的例子
John, if I don't have any John
如果我的通讯录里
on my address book, we basically
根本就没有 John 我们基本只能
tell back Siri that I don't have
告诉 Siri 通讯录中没有 John
it and it's not supported.
无法支持这个请求
It will make Siri to ask the
这将导致 Siri 请求用户
user to provide a valid
提供一个有效的
recipient.
接收者名称
In the case where we found one,
如果我们在通讯录中找到一个 John
we need to process that
我们需要处理那个
recipient.
接收者
So, let me walk through this
那么 我来演示一下
piece of code.
这段代码
The first thing that we're going
我们要做的第一件事
to do is validate if that
是确认
recipient that we found has one
我们找到的那个接收者是否有一个
or multiple handles.
或多个联系方式
This case, we are focusing on
这里 我们将要关注的是
the phone numbers.
电话号码
Where there are more than one
如果电话号码
phone number and we cannot make
不止一个 而且我们无法
the decision for the user, we're
替用户做出决定
going to return back a
那么我们就要返回一个
disambiguation response code
消除歧义的响应代码
with the handle that we want to
同时包括我们想要
display.
展示的联系方式
This is going to be used by Siri
Siri 将会用它
to ask to the user which of the
询问用户
handles you want to use.
究竟想要使用哪个句柄
In the case where we have a
如果我们的通讯录里只有一个
single recipient with a single
接收者 只带有一个联系方式
handle, we basically return
我们通常都返回
success.
“成功”值
We tell them we found the
告诉他们说  我们已经找到
recipient and we're ready to
接收者 并且已经准备
move on to the next stage.
进入下一个步骤
Have a special case here.
这里有一种特殊情况
This special case, it will cause
在这种特殊情况下
Siri to make a question to user.
Siri 会向用户询问
Are you sure you want to message
“您确定要
John?
给 John 发送消息吗”
I use this in the cases where I
在有些情况下我用到这个办法 比如
do some level of fuzzy matching
当我在进行某种程度的模糊匹配时
when the contact that Siri got
这时 Siri 被询问的联系人
requested doesn't completely
跟我通讯录中的
match to the one I have on my
联系人并不完全
address book.
匹配
We're missing one or more case
我们或多或少还会错过
to handle.
要处理的情况
This is a case where we have
在这个例子里 我们得到的
more than one match.
匹配结果不止一个
As we saw, we have John Baily
正如我们所见 我的通讯录里有
and John Appleseed on my address
John Baily 和 John Appleseed
book, so we need to disambiguate
所以我们需要消除这二者之间
between them.
的歧义
Here we're using the same
在此我们还将使用同样的
technique, using a
技术手段 要使用
disambiguation and providing the
消除歧义列表 然后提供
list of matches.
匹配列表
There is one more case.
还有一种情况
As we saw on the flow that we
正如我们在刚才的流程中所看见的
walked through, first we asked
首先我们已经要求给 John 发送消息
with John and then when the user
然后当用户
picked John Baily we asked which
选择 John Baily 后 我们又问他要选择哪个
handle.
联系方式
We are going to call back the
我们将重新调用
resolveRecipients intent
resolveRecipients intent
parameter and we need to handle
参数 我们需要处理
that case.
这种情况
In that case, we need to
在这种情况下 我们需要确认
validate if the handle has been
是否已经提供了联系方式
already provided, we can
我们基本上可以
basically return back with that
那位接收者
recipient.
作为返回值
So, let's see this in action.
那么 我们来看看它的具体操作
In order to do that, I'm going
为了做到这一点 我将要
to use the edit a scheme.
使用编辑方案
So, you can provide the Siri
所以你可以从一开始就为 Siri 提供
intent query from the get go so
intent 询问 所以
you actually have to trigger
实际上你必须要触发
Siri and speak to it.
Siri 并对它讲话
So, when I run my example, it's
所以 当我演示这个例子时
going to trigger Siri for me and
就是要触发 Siri
it's going to say text John
就是要对它说
hello on UnicornChat.
“在 UnicornChat 上给 John 发送‘Hello’”
As we see, we have multiple
我们看到了
Johns on my address book, so we
我的通讯录中有好几个 John
need to pick one.
所以我们需要选择其中一位
Let's pick John Baily.
我们来选一下 John Baily
As we walk through the flow, we
我们在经历这个流程时
also have to pick a handle.
还必须要选择一个联系方式
In this case, we want to pick
在这里 我们想选择
the mobile handle.
手机联系方式
At this point, we are ready to
这时 我们已经准备好
send the message and all the--
发送消息 而且所有的
the recipient has been resolved.
这位接收者也已经被解析出来了
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
We just saw how to walk through
我们刚刚看到了
the process of resolving a
在发送消息时
contact when trying to send a
如何确定联系人的
message.
过程
This technique also applies to
这种技巧也适用于
any other intent that requires
其他需要对联系人
contact resolution.
进行解析的 intent
Messaging applications are great
使用短信 App 来发送消息
for sending messages, but
感觉很棒 不过用它们
they're also great for reading
来读取消息
messages.
也很棒
A great example of that is
举一个很好的例子
reading messages on CarPlay.
那就是用 CarPlay 读取信息
If your application implements
如果你的应用执行了
the INSearchForMessagesIntent,
INSearchForMessagesIntent
you will get access to reading
你就可以获取
experience on iOS as well as on
在 iOS 以及 CarPlay 上的
CarPlay.
阅读记录
So, on iOS 11, we introduce a
所以 我们在 iOS 11 里引入了
new property to make replying to
一种新属性 通过它能够
the messages that Siri just read
更方便地回复 Siri 刚向我们的用户
to our users easier.
读出的信息
That new property is
这种新属性叫做
conversationIdentifier.
conversationIdentifier
This has been introduced on the
它已经被采用于
INMessage object as well on the
INMessage 对象 以及
INSendMessageIntent.
INSendMessageIntent
This conversationIdentifier is
这个 conversationIdentifier
going to be used to reply to a
将会被用来回复
message.
消息
Siri is going to read a message
Siri 将为你读出
for you from UnicornChat and the
来自 UnicornChat 的消息
value of this property is going
这一属性的值将
to help you to short circuit the
帮助你缩短
contact resolution process that
联系人解析过程
we walked through.
这个我们刚刚演示过
Let's see the flow of how this
现在我们来看看这个流程是怎样
is done.
完成的
Read my messages on UnicornChat.
“查看我在 UnicornChat 上的消息”
We want to read the messages
我们想查看一下我们在
that we have on the UnicornChat.
UnicornChat 上收到的消息
Siri clearly understands that.
Siri 清楚地理解了我们的要求
Siri is going to send an
Siri 将发送一个
INSearchForMessagesIntent to
INSearchForMessagesIntent
your app extension.
到你的 app extension
Your app extension has
你的 app extension 已经
implemented the
执行了
SearchForMessageIntent handle.
SearchForMessageIntent 句柄
This handle is going to provide
这个句柄将提供
the list of INMessages object
INMessages 对象列表
that Siri is going to read back
Siri 会将这个列表读取给
to the user.
用户
As we notice, the INMessage
我们都注意到了 INMessage
object contains a property named
对象包含了一个属性 它名为
conversationIdentifier.
conversationIdentifier
This identifier represents the
这个标识符代表着
uniqueness of that conversation.
该会话的独特性
With that uniqueness, you can
由于这种独特性的存在 如果用户想要
use that conversationIdentifier
予以回复的话
when the user wants to reply
你就可以
back.
使用那个 conversationIdentifier 了
As we see, Siri finished reading
正如我们所见 Siri 在读完
the message and it will ask the
消息之后 会询问用户
user if they want to reply.
他们是否想要回复此消息
To continue this flow, let's
为了继续这个流程 我们不妨
assume the user wants to reply
假设用户想要回复说
saying hello.
“你好”
Siri clearly understands the
Siri 清楚地理解了
user say just hello, meaning I
用户只说了“你好” 意思是
want to reply to this message
我想回复这条消息
and I want it to say hello on my
并且回复的内容是
content.
“你好”
Siri is going to send down an
Siri 将会发送一个
INSendMessageIntent with a
INSendMessageIntent
conversationIdentifier
并附有已输入数据的
populated.
conversationIdentifier
This conversationIdentifier
这个 conversationIdentifier
value is the same one that you
的值就是你在 INMessage 对象上
populated on the INMessage
输入的相同值
object that Siri used for
Siri 正是通过它来
reading the message.
读取消息
With this value, now it's
关于这个值  现在它
provided in the
也被提供给
resolveRecipients intent
resolveRecipients intent
parameter.
参数中
Would it-- we can short circuit
我们可以缩短
the contact resolution by
联系人的解析过程
basically using it and going
基本上就是利用这个值
straight to our messaging
然后直接进入消息会话
conversation, grabbing that
抓取这个会话
conversation, getting the
选择接收者
recipients, and moving on to the
然后进入下一步
next step of replying to the
也就是说
message.
回复消息
To learn more about enabling
想进一步了解如何
your app for CarPlay, I
在 CarPlay 中启用你的 App
recommend you take a look to
我推荐大家去看看
this video that we released this
我们今年发布的这个
year.
视频
In addition to doing contact
除了关注联系人解析之外
resolution, we also had looked
我们还致力于研究
at response codes.
响应代码
Last year, when we introduced
去年 当我们推出
SiriKit, we introduced a set of
SiriKit 时 也推出了一套
response codes that you might be
响应代码 你们在短信服务领域里
familiar with on the messaging
或许已经很熟悉这些
world.
响应代码了
For example, when the service is
我举个例子 如果服务不可用
not available, you can return
你可以返回一条
back a failure service not
“故障 服务不可用”
available and Siri will gladly
Siri 将很乐意
tell that to the user what went
告知用户是哪里
wrong.
出了问题
We look at that and we have
我们关注这一点 而且已经
improved the response codes on
改进了相关响应代码
calling intents, messaging
即通话意图 短信意图
intents, and payment intents.
和支付意图的响应代码
In this case, I have an example
关于这种情况 我再举个例子
of a call intent where we
如果有一个呼叫意图 在我们引入一个
introduced an invalid number
无效号码的
response code and it will help
响应代码后
us to be more transparent to the
它会帮助我们更清楚地
user when the intent created
告知用户 这个新创建的
doesn't have a valid number.
intent 缺少一个有效号码
That way Siri will provide a
Siri 将以这种方式而提供一种
nice experience and it will be
很棒的体验 它会
pretty clear what went wrong.
很清楚哪里出了问题
For more information for this,
若想了解更多相关信息
you can look at the
大家可以查看一下
documentation.
这方面的文稿
To recap what we have covered so
现在扼要总结一下我们讲解过的内容
far, we talked about
我们谈到了
INPerson.siriMatches, the new
INPerson.SiriMatches 这是
property that we introduced on
我们引入 iOS 10.3 的新属性
iOS 10.3 that can help you do
它可以帮助你
better contact resolution
进行更准确的联系人解析
handling.
处理
After that, we walked through
在这之后 我们演示了
the process of resolving
如何解析
multiple handles, meaning
多个句柄的过程  也就是
multiple phone numbers or email
它包含了多个电话号码
addresses or a combination of
或者电邮地址 或两方面都存在这种
both.
情况
We also covered the introduction
我们还介绍了
of the conversationIdentifier
conversationIdentifier
and how it's helpful to replying
以及它如何有效帮助用户回复
messages that Siri just read.
Siri 读过的短信消息
And we also briefly covered
我们还简要谈到了
response codes and the
响应代码以及
enhancement we have provided in
我们已在 iOS 11 里提供的
iOS 11.
改进措施
With that, I'm going to hand
接下来 我要把讲台让给
over to my coworker Rohit so he
我的合作者 Rohit 让他
can talk to you more about
来给你们讲解更多关于
security.
安全性的内容
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Angel.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Angel
Hello everyone.
大家好
My name is Rohit Dasari.
我叫 Rohit Dasari
I work on the SiriKit team.
是 SiriKit 团队的一员
So, let's talk about security in
现在 我们来谈谈
the context of SiriKit.
SiriKit 语境的安全性
Let's go back to the example of
我们再回到
UnicornChat which we saw
先前演示过的 UnicornChat 的
earlier.
例子
You see here that the user is
大家看这里 用户可以
able to send a message even when
发送消息 即使
the device is locked.
设备处于锁屏状态
Now, Siri lets this through
现在 Siri 做到了
makes-- Siri makes a decision
Siri 做出决定的
based on the intent whether--
基础  是 intent 能否
how to balance usability and
如何平衡可用性与
convenience with security.
有安全保障的便捷性
In this case, for the messaging
在这个短信的例子中
case, Siri lets requests through
Siri 实现了这些请求
even when the device is locked.
尽管设备是处于锁屏状态
Some of you might be required to
你们有些人可能需要
ask the user to unlock the
先让用户解锁设备
device before handling intents
然后再处理
of this kind.
这一类的意图
This might be due to some
这可能是出于某些
security policies or some
安全政策或者某些
corporate or legal requirements
公司或法律的要求
that your app has to conform to.
你的 App 必须遵循这些要求
There's a way to do this with
运用目前的 SiriKit 机制
the current SiriKit mechanisms
就有办法做到这一点
without any code changes.
而不必更改任何代码
That is zero code changes.
这就是零代码变更
All you have to do is go into
你只需要进入
the info.plist of your SiriKit
SiriKit intents Extension 里的
intents extension and in the
Info.plist 文件 以及你列举的
place where you list the intents
自己的 Extension 所支持的
that your extension supports,
各种 intents
add this entry for the intents
你需要为你想要限制的 intents
you want to restrict.
创建这个条目
The section is called
字段名为
IntentsRestrictedWhileLocked,
IntentsRestrictedWhileLocked
which speaks for itself.
这个名称已经说明自身性质了
So, with this one change, Siri
那么  经过这个改动 现在 Siri
now knows that when the user
知道了 当用户
wants to perform an intent which
想要执行一个
falls into this category, the
属于该类别的 intent 时
device must first be unlocked.
首先要给设备解锁
Zero lines of code change.
一行代码都不用更改
But sometimes that's not enough.
但有时这还不够
Unlocking the device is not
只是去解锁设备 仍然
enough.
不够
Let's take this example of an
让我们以这个 App 为例
app which users can use to lock
用户可以用这个 App
and unlock their cars.
锁定和解锁他们的汽车
For an app like this to
对于这样一个 App
integrate with SiriKit, it has
要与 SiriKit 集成
to handle an intent called
就必须处理一个 intent 它名为
setCarLockStatusIntent.
setCarLockStatusIntent
This is an intent we added in
这个 intent 我们已添加到了
iOS 10.3.
iOS 10.3
Let's take a quick look at this
让我们快速看一下这个
intent.
intent
It's a pretty simple intent.
它相当简单
There are two properties.
其中包含两个属性
The name of the car you want to
你想要锁定的
lock or unlock and the state
或者是解锁的车名  以及
that you want to set on that
你想给汽车设定的
car.
状态
Once the app provides an
只要这个 App 提供了
extension that handles this
处理此 intent 的 extension
intent, it can handle commands
它就可以处理这样的指令
like this where the user can say
例如 用户可以说
unlock my car and Siri will know
“给我的车解锁” Siri 就知道
to invoke the app extension,
要调用这个 app extension
give it intent, and let the
给它一个 intent 然后让这个
intent-- and let the extension
intent 让这个extension
handle it.
来处理
Notice I'm not saying the name
请注意 我现在不会提到
of the app here.
这个 App 的名字
This is because Siri is smart
因为 Siri 很智能  如果设备里
enough to know when there is
只有一个符合条件的 App
only one qualifying app to
可以处理某个特定的 intent
handle a particular intent and
它都会发现
it will not ask the user for
Siri 不会要求用户
either confirming the name of
确认这个 App 的名称
the app or for disambiguating.
或要求客户消除歧义
So, with this intent handled,
所以 处理完这个 intent
the example app I have reflects
我的示例 App 就将
the change in the state of the
车门状态的变化
car's doors by showing it
以图像方式反映了出来
graphically, as you can see
大家在这里
here.
也可以看到
So, this is a pretty sensitive
所以这是一个很灵敏的
transaction.
传输处理
You are unlocking somebody's
你正在解锁某人
car.
的汽车
So, for transactions like this,
那么 对于这种传输处理
even when the device is
即使设备处于锁屏状态
unlocked, you might want to
你可能也想
present another authorization
向用户提出另一种
request to the user.
授权请求
We recommend you use the secure
我们推荐大家使用
authorization mechanism which is
安全授权机制
already built into iOS, which is
它已经被加入 iOS
Touch ID.
那就是 Touch ID
Using the local authentication
利用本机授权验证 API
API, you can even customize the
你甚至可以自定义
prompt which is shown along with
与 Touch ID 一同出现的提示
the Touch ID to tell the user to
告诉用户
give the user some context about
让用户了解一下原因
why they're being asked to
为什么要求他们
authorize all over again even
再次授权
when the device is locked--
尽管设备已经锁定
unlocked.
已经解锁
In case your device does not--
如果你的设备不支持
in case the user's device does
如果用户的设备
not support Touch ID or maybe
不支持 Touch ID 或者可能
the user has not configured
用户还未
Touch ID yet on that device, the
在其设备上配置 Touch ID
local authentication API allows
本机验证 API 只允许你
you to fall back to unlocking
通过密码
the device using just the
来解锁设备
You notice it has the same
大家注意 它的
customized string which is
自定义字符串
provided by your app over here
与你的 App 在此提供的内容相同
to give the user some context.
它可以给用户提供某种语境
This is pretty simple to do.
这操作起来很简单
Let me show you a demo of how to
我给大家演示一下
do it.
如何操作
So, what I have here is the
那么  我在这里显示的
intent handler for the
intent 处理程序
setCarLockStatusIntent of the
用于 setCarLockStatusIntent
test app I just showed you.
它来自我刚给大家看的测试用 App
Let us see what this app looks
我们来看看这个 App
like.
是什么样的
As we saw, there is a
我们看到了 这里有一张
representation of the car, of
代表汽车的图片
the user's car, and this also
是用户汽车的图片 它同时也代表了
represents the state of the car,
汽车的状态
whether it's locked or unlocked.
是属于锁定 还是解锁
In this case, it's locked and I
现在 汽车处于锁定状态
can unlock it with a tap.
我点击一下就可以将车门打开
Set it to the lock state and I
现在把它设置为锁定状态 然后我
want to ask Siri to unlock the
又想让 Siri
car using this app.
用这个 App 解锁汽车
So, as my colleague Angel showed
那么 正如我的同事 Angel 先前展示的那样
earlier, I'm going to use the
我将要使用
scheme editor to enter the
方案编辑器来输入
request I want to send to Siri
我想要发送给 Siri 的请求
and I'm going to issue the
我将发送这个
request.
请求
The scheme editor is very handy,
方案编辑器十分好用
in case you haven't realized.
说不准大家还没意识到这一点
It saves you the trouble of
有了它 你在测试时不用再
speaking to your phone when you
那么费劲地
are testing, which is really
对着手机讲话
useful in a shared workspace
这在共享工作环境中
environment.
非常实用
So, in this case, Siri has
所以 在这种情况下 Siri
handled the request, given it to
处理了该请求  把它
the app, and has reported
传递给了 App
success.
并且报告成功
Let us confirm that it actually
我们来确认一下
did unlock the car.
它确实把汽车给解锁了
So, now the car is-- state is
现在汽车所处的状态
update-- is updated to show that
已经更新 可以看出
it has been unlocked.
它已经解锁
Let's go back to the intent
我们再回过头来看
handler.
意图句柄
This intent handler extracts the
这个意图句柄提取了
fields that we saw on the
我们在 intent 上看到的字段
intent, which is should I lock
内容是  我该给汽车上锁
the car or unlock the car and
还是解锁汽车
the-- and it looks up an
而且 它会寻找
internal car object matching the
与 intent 上面名称相符的
name on the intent.
内部汽车对象
Then it sets the lock state on
然后 它根据 intent 上的输入
the car object based on the
将汽车对象设置为
input on the intent.
锁定状态
And, finally, after having--
最后  在更改了
after having changed the state
汽车的状态之后
of the car, it returns a success
它向 Siri 返回了
response to Siri.
成功响应代码
In case of a failure or in case
如果操作失败
when there is no-- when there is
或者是 intent 上没有
not enough information on the
没有足够的信息
intent, it returns a failure
它就会返回
response.
失败响应代码
So, you notice how that this
所以 你们都看到了
extent-- this intent handler is
这个意图句柄是怎样
unconditionally handling the
无条件地处理了
request that the user gave it.
用户给它的请求
We want to add a prompt here
我们想在这里添加一个提示
using the local authentication
利用本机验证
API.
API
So, once we confirmed that the
所以 一旦我们确认了
intent has all the parameters we
该 intent 具备我们所需的所有参数
need, let's call the local
我们就可以调用
authentication API.
本机验证 API
In order to call the local
为了调用
generating a string based on the
首先我要生成一个字符串
lock state that is requested.
它是基于提请实施的锁定状态
That is if it is-- if the user
也就是说 如果用户
wants me to lock the car, then I
要求我锁定汽车
will show the appropriate
我就会显示适当的
prompt.
提示
Then, to the local
然后
authentication context, I'm
针对本机验证的语境
going to ask it to evaluate a
我将会要求它评估
certain policy.
某个特定策略
In this case, I'm asking it to
在这个例子中 我将要求它
evaluate the device owner
评估设备所有人的
authentication policy.
授权行为
This is a policy which attempts
这个策略  首先是尝试
to do a Touch ID prompt first
给出 Touch ID 提示
and if that doesn't work it
如果不成功
falls back to the device
它会转而要求
passcode prompt.
设备密码提示
Next, I pass in the prompt
接下来 我要输入提示字符串
string which I just generated in
这是我刚在前一行生成的提示字符串
the previous line, and finally I
最后  我就获得了
have the reply block.
回复代码块
So, let's fill in the reply
那么 我们来填充一下这个
If the user has granted access
如果用户以 Touch ID 或
via Touch ID or a device
设备密码提示的方式
passcode prompt, I'm going to go
同意访问  我将继续操作
ahead and change the state of
并更改汽车的状态
the car as I did earlier without
就像我先前没有提示的情况下一样
prompting, but this time I'm
不过这一次
actually waiting for the user to
我其实是在等待用户
give me access.
授权我访问
And then I'm going to call the
接着 我将调用
completion block with the
完成代码块  方法是
success response to tell Siri
以成功的响应代码
that request has been completed
来告诉 Siri
successfully.
请求已经成功执行
I also need to tell Siri when
如果出现了失败
there is a failure, that is if
我也需要告诉 Siri
the access was not granted, then
也就是说  如果授权访问未获通过
I need to tell Siri that there
那么我就需要告诉 Siri
was a failure.
请求失败
I do that by returning a failure
要完成该操作 我需要使用
response using the same
相同的完成代码块
completion block.
来返回一个失败的响应代码
So, with this change, let us go
那么 在做出这个变动之后
and see if unlocking the car
我们再来看看  解锁汽车的过程中
prompts the user to do
会不会提示用户
authentication.
进行验证
So, let's restore the car state
所以 我们来把汽车
back to being locked and run
还原到锁定状态
this.
然后运行这个
I'm using the same request as
我的请求与前面使用的相同
earlier, which is unlock my car.
也就是 解锁汽车
So, you notice during the Siri
你们看 在 Siri 请求的期间
request a prompt comes up.
出现了一个提示
If the simulator was configured
如果这个模拟器设置了
to do a Touch ID, it would have
Touch ID 它就会
shown a Touch ID prompt.
显示一个 Touch ID 提示
In this case, I configured it to
在这种情况下 我给它设置了
do device passcode prompt.
设备密码提示
So, let me enter my super secure
现在 我要输入我的超级安全
password.
密码
Please look away.
请不要偷看哦
And once I've entered the
一旦我输入了
password, the request went
密码 这个请求
through.
就通过了
Let us confirm that it actually
让我们启动 App
went through by launching the
来确认一下  这个请求确实
app.
完成了
Yep. The car was unlocked.
没错  汽车已经解锁了
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, with a few lines of code, we
所以 运用几行代码
were able to add a local
我们就能在 Siri 的请求过程中
authentication prompt during a
添加一个
Siri request.
本地授权提示
Using the local authentication
利用本机验证 API
API allows you to do multiple
可以让你进行
forms of authentication.
多种形式的验证
Touch ID, if supported and
比如说 Touch ID 它是否已被支持并且
configured, or a device passcode
完成配置  或者  它是否使用
if not.
设备密码
The place where you call this
大家调用这个
local authentication API is in
本机验证 API 的位置
the handle method of your intent
是在调用完成代码块之前
handler before calling the
意图句柄的
completion block.
处理方法里面
And because the local
而且 因为这个
authentication framework is part
本机验证框架是系统的一部分
of the system, Siri knows to
所以 Siri 知道
coordinate with it so that if
要与它相协调 因此
the user has made a request over
如果用户发出的请求
Hey Siri, then the request waits
是通过“Hey Siri”该请求就需要
for the user for a prompt to be
等待用户对提示
responded to.
作出回应
To learn more about the local
若想了解更多
authentication API, we refer you
关于本机验证 API 的信息
to this talk from 2014.
建议参考 2014 年以来这方面的发言内容
Some of you might be working on
你们当中有些人正在研发的 App 里
apps which require a payment to
可能有一些
be completed before a Siri
在执行 Siri 请求之前
request can be satisfied.
还需要完成一个付款操作
In this example, the user wants
在这个样例里  用户想要
to book a RainbowCar on
在 UnicornRides 上
UnicornRides and you need a
预约一辆 RainbowCar
payment to be made from the user
你在接受请求之前
before you can accept this
需要让用户完成付款
We recommend you use the secure
我们推荐大家使用
Apple Pay API for handling
安全的 Apple Pay API
payment transactions during your
以便处理 Siri 请求期间的
Siri request.
付款交易
Using the Apply Pay API gives
使用 Apple Pay API
you the same advantages as using
能给你带来各种好处
the local authentication API,
就像使用本机验证 API 一样
which is you get coordination
也就是 你要与 Siri 协调
with Siri and the place where
而且你调用这个 API
you could call this API is in
的位置  就是你在
the same place that is in the
调用完成代码块之前
handle method before you call
处理方法里的
the completion block.
相同位置
Now let's talk about teaching
现在 我们来谈谈如何
Siri new words.
把新词教给 Siri
Let's take this example of an
我们这次用一个名为
app called UnicornPay which
UnicornPay 的 App 为例
allows the user to query account
该 App 允许用户
balances on their accounts.
查询他们的账户余额
This-- an app like this might
像这样的 App 还可以
also allow users to give names
允许用户为应用里的
to accounts in the app.
各账户设置名称
Now, these names are user
现在可以看到 这些名字都是用户配置的
configured, so they need not be
它们不一定是
real English words.
真正的英语单词
In this example, we have an
在这个例子里 我们有一个
account called NestEgg, which
名为 NestEgg 的账户
would have been a word, except
这原本是一个单词
there is no space.
只不过中间没有空格
So, it's made of two English
所以 它是由两个英语单词构成
words, which, without help, Siri
如果没有帮助
might not be able to recognize.
Siri 可能无法识别它
When we introduced SiriKit last
去年 我们在介绍 SiriKit 时
year, we talked about some
谈到了一些机制
mechanisms that will allow you
这些机制可以允许你
to help Siri understand words
帮助 Siri 理解
like these.
类似于这样的单词
These words are not unique to an
这些单词并不是某个 App 所特有
app, but are unique to a
而是该 App 的某个
particular user of that app.
特定用户所特有
Examples of these are names of
比如
photo albums, names of workouts,
相簿名称 健身名称
and so on.
等等
The mechanism that we recommend
我们推荐一个
you use to teach Siri these
用来教会 Siri 这些单词的办法
words is the INVocabulary API.
它是 INVocabulary API
To get a refresher about custom
如果想获得更新的
vocabulary introduction, we
自定义词汇介绍
refer you to these talks from
建议大家关注一下去年
last year when we introduced
我们介绍 SiriKit 的演讲内容
SiriKit, but today let's dive
不过 今天我们还要更加
deeper into the INVocabulary
深入地了解一下 INVocabulary
API.
API
The API is pretty simple.
这个 API 相当简单
It has one method which takes an
其中有一个方法
NSOrderedSet of vocabulary
是采用了词汇字符串的有序集合 NSOrderedSet
strings and this set is meant
这个集合适用于
for a particular vocabulary item
某个特定的词汇项目
type.
类型
For example, a photo album name
比如 相簿名称
or a workout name.
或健身名称
Note that this is an ordered
注意 这是一个有序的集合
set, which means that Siri gives
这就意味着 Siri 会
preference to the words towards
优先选择靠近
the beginning of the set.
集合起始点的单词
But also note that these are
不过请注意
strings that you're teaching
这些也是你将要教会 Siri 的
Siri.
字符串
Plain strings with no context
单纯的字符串
around them.
没有语境
That might have some
这也许会有一些
limitations.
局限性
Let us see what those
让我们进一步
limitations are by diving deeper
深入了解它的实际运作
into how this would actually
来看看它有哪些
work.
局限性
Here we have an application
我们现在有一个应用
where in its private store has
它的私人存储器里
some accounts which are named by
有一些已被用户命名的
the user.
账户
To tell Siri about these
为了把这些帐户告诉 Siri
accounts, the app would use the
这个 App 将使用
INVocabulary API and send those
INVocabulary API
strings using the API which we
并将使用这些字符串的 API 发送出去
just saw.
这个我们已看到过
With this knowledge, now Siri is
有了这方面的知识储备
aware of these new words and the
现在 Siri 就认识这些新词了
next time the user makes a
等到下一次用户请求
request that uses one of these
使用其中某个单词时
words, Siri is capable of
Siri 便能
looking up the knowledge that
查找该 App 赋予
the app has given it and
它的知识内容
identifying candidates in the
并从用户的输入中
user's input that match a custom
确认与类似的自定义单词
word like this and recognize it
相匹配的候选词
correctly as the user would
并且予以正确识别
expect to see.
从而符合用户的期待
Now, once this word has been
好 一旦识别出这个词
recognized, Siri will be able to
Siri 便可以
give this word to the
把它传递给
application's intents extension
应用的 intents extension
and expect it to use that word
并期望它用这个词来
to look up the corresponding
查找存储器中
object in the store.
相应的对象
But note that this is just a
不过 请注意这只是
plain string with no context
一个单纯的字符串
around it.
没有相关语境
So, your application might not
所以 你的应用也许
have enough information to look
并没有足够的信息来
it up unambiguously.
准确查找出这个它词
It might have to-- it might have
也许需要
to do fuzzy match, it might not
进行模糊匹配
be an index based on the string
或许这并不是基于
in your application store.
应用存储器里字符串的索引
So, this is not an ideal
因此 这不是一种理想的
situation.
情况
In iOS 11, we thought we could
我们认为在 iOS 11 里
make this better.
我们会做得更好
We added this new API which
我们添加的这个新型 API
allows you to send Siri
它将允许你给 Siri 发送对象
objects-- any objects-- as long
任何对象
as they conform to an
只要它们遵循
INSpeakable protocol.
INSpeakable 协议
Again, these objects have to be
再强调一下 这些对象
in an ordered set which follow
必须是一个有序集合
the same rules as the strings in
与之前 API 里的字符串
the older API and they are meant
遵循相同的原则
for a particular parameter type.
并且适用于某种特定的参数类型
Let's take a deeper look at what
现在我们来深入了解一下
this protocol is.
这个协议内容
The INSpeakable protocol is a
INSpeakable 协议
detailed description of the
详细描述了
vocabulary item that you are
你将教授 Siri 的
teaching Siri.
词汇项
The main parts of it-- the main
该协议的主要部分
property on it is the actual
它的主要属性就是
word that you're teaching Siri.
你正在教 Siri 的这个实际单词
In this case, it would be the
在这个例子中 它可以是
word NestEgg without a space in
NestEgg 这个中间缺少空格的单词
it or some other creative
或其他编造误拼的
misspelling of a workout name or
某个健身训练名称
it could even be a word which
甚至可以是一个
has mixed in numbers or special
混合了数字或特殊字符
characters.
的单词
You can also teach Siri-- you
你还可以教会 Siri
can also give Siri hints about
还可以给 Siri 一些提示
how to recognize the words that
告诉它如何识别
you are teaching it.
你正在教它的单词
In this case, they are spelled
在这个例子里 它们采用了
in a sounds-like pattern, which
一种发音近似的拼写方式
is the same pattern you would
你会采用同样的方式
use for configuring phonetic
来配置联系人 App 里
names in your contacts app.
的语音名称
With each INSpeakable object,
对于每个 INSpeakable 对象
you can also provide a
你还可以
vocabulary identifier which can
提供一个词汇标识符
uniquely identify this object in
它可以单独识别
your app store.
App Store 里的对象
We-- it's a plain string, so we
我们这是一个纯文本的字符串
don't restrict what value you
因此 我们不会限制
can give this identifier, but
你赋予该标识符的值
using a unique grid or something
但是如果使用某个独特的 Grid
like that will help you match
或类似的东西  将有助于你
this object unambiguously in
在 App 数据存储器中
your app's data store.
准确地匹配该对象
Finally, the INSpeakable
最后 INSpeakable 协议
protocol also allows Siri to
还允许 Siri
provide alternative matches for
提供单词的其他匹配形式
words which the-- which Siri
也就是 Siri 认为
thinks the user might mean.
用户可能想要的匹配
This is analogous to the
这相当于
siriMatches property that my
SiriMatches 的属性
college Angel talked about
我的同事 Angel 之前讲解过这个
earlier where an INPerson object
如果 INPerson 对象
which actually does conform to
确实是要遵循
the INSpeakable protocol can
INSpeakable 协议
have candidate alternative
那么它便会显示出像 SiriMatches 那样的
matches exposed as siriMatches.
候选备用匹配
With this new protocol and API,
有了这个新协议和 API
let us take a look again at the
现在我们再回到同一个示例
same example and see how things
看看这些变化是
have changed.
如何发生的
So, the application wants to
那么 现在这个应用想要
tell Siri about the same two
把同样两个具有
account objects with the
自定义名称的账户对象
customized names.
告诉 Siri
It would call the INVocabulary
它将调用 INVocabulary API
API, but this time it would give
不过 这一次它将把
it the objects themselves and
对象本身传给 Siri
Siri will use those INSpeakable
然后 Siri 将会使用
parts of these objects and when
这些对象中的 INSpeakable 部分
the user says a request that has
而当用户发出请求时
a word which matches this new
它所包含的某个词汇
object that Siri has learned
与 Siri 学过的新对象相匹配
about, Siri will recognize the
Siri 将识别出这个模式
pattern and replace it with the
并将它替换成
expected spelling and when
预期的拼写形式
communicating back to the app's
而且 当 Siri 将信息传回到 App 的
intent extension, instead of
Intent Extension 时
giving it a plain string without
Siri 不会提供没有任何语境的
any context, Siri will now give
纯文本字符串  而是会给它
it the INSpeakable object.
INSpeakable 对象
Because this INSpeakable object
因为这个 INSpeakable 对象
has the vocabulary identifier,
带有词汇标识符
which, as I said earlier, could
如前所述
be a unique ID for that object.
它可以是该对象特有的 ID
The lookup on the app side for
从 App 这方面来说 查找此对象
this object becomes easier.
会变得更容易
So, we hope that with this new
所以 我们希望有了这个新的
API requests like this where the
API 请求之后
user is able to issue a request
用户能够使用某个自定义词汇
with a custom vocabulary word to
向 Siri 发出请求
Siri, your app can handle them
那么你的 App 就可以处理这些请求
without worrying about doing
而不必担心会出现
fuzzy matching against your app
要在你的 App Store 实现
store.
模糊匹配
The other example where you
在另一个例证里  你也有可能
might want to teach Siri new
想教 Siri 学些新词
words is when there's a word
那就是  当某个词
which is unique to your app, but
在你的 App 里有特殊含义 但是它对
common to all users of your app.
这个 App 的所有使用者来说都很普通
An example of this would be a
这方面的例证  可以是
ride-booking app which has a
某个行程预定 App
branded or a customized vehicle
其中涉及到品牌车名  或是自定义的
name or a workout app which
交通工具名称
might have a non-English workout
抑或是某个非英语体能训练 App
name.
的名称
In order to teach Siri words
为了把这样的单词教给 Siri
like this, we recommend that you
我们推荐你
use the
使用
AppIntentVocabulary.plist.
AppIntentVocabulary.plist
Once you provide a plist to
一旦你向 Siri 提供了一个 plist 文件
Siri, in examples like this
比如说 像这样的例子
where a ride-booking app has
行程预定 App
customized its ride names--
已经自定义了行程名称
which are not real words in this
在这个例子中 它们并不是真正的单词
case, as you can see--
大家可以看到
RainbowCar without a space is
中间没留空格的 RainbowCar
not a real word.
并不是真正的单词
Users can now say the words and
用户现在可以说出这些词
expect Siri to recognize them.
并期待 Siri 能予以识别
The way you would register words
把这样的词汇
like this with Siri is to use
记载到 Siri 的方法 就是
the custom vocabulary plist
使用自定义词汇 plist 文件
where the main pieces are the
它里面的主要部分是
intent parameter for which you
intent 参数  是你用来
are providing the custom
提供自定义词汇项的
vocabulary item.
Intent 参数
In this case, this parameter
在这种情况下 这个参数
would itself be of type
本身就可能属于
INSpeakable and inside that
INSpeakable 类型
parameter the subfields of the
在参数内部 INSpeakable 对象的
INSpeakable object can be
子字段可以被
specified.
具体指定
For example, you can give a
例如 你可以
vocabulary identifier for the
指定一个词汇标识符
SparkleCar which you are
用来识别你正在教 Siri
teaching Siri about, and the
辨认的 SparkleCar
actual name that you're teaching
以及你以口语词组形式
Siri as the spoken phrase, and
教给 Siri 的实际名称
the pronunciation hint, similar
或者是发音提示
to the one we saw in the earlier
类似于我们在前面例子里看到的
case for user-specific
针对用户特定词汇
vocabulary.
的标识符
Having done this, Siri will now
完成这些之后 Siri
be able to understand requests
将能够理解这类请求
like this where the user is
也就是 当用户
using the customized vocabulary
正在使用自定义词汇
word which are specific to your
而它们对于你的 App
app.
又属于特定词汇的时候
Now let's talk about how you can
现在 我们来谈谈
test the quality of SiriKit
如何利用 UI 测试
integration with UI testing.
来检测 SiriKit 的集成质量
We introduced UI testing a
几年前 我们介绍过 UI 测试
couple of years ago as a
这种机制可以让你
mechanism for you to write UI
在 Xcode 项目内部
tests-- automation tests--
编写 UI 测试
inside your project in Xcode.
自动化测试
Now that Siri is supported in
现在 Siri 在这个模拟器里
the simulator, you can run these
已经获得支持  你可以在任何
tests on any hardware
硬件配置中运行这些测试
configuration without actually
而不需要
requiring to have the hardware
真正地携带使用
with you.
这个硬件
These UI tests are automatable,
UI 测试实现了自动化
so you can keep them running
因此你可以让它们
automatedly in your CI pipelines
在 CI 管道或自定义集成管道里
or custom integration pipelines
持续自动运行
to make sure that code changes
从而确保代码变化
are not breaking existing
不会破坏现有的
functionality.
功能性质
Using these UI tests also gives
使用这些 UI 测试还能带给你
you a certain degree of language
某种程度上的语言独立性
independence, that way you can
这样一来 你就能够
test Siri integration in a
使用自身成长过程中使用的
language which is not the
初始语言以外的
primary language of your
另一种语言来测试
development.
Siri 的集成效果
We will see an example of this
我们稍后将会看到这方面的
shortly.
例子
For further info about UI
关于 UI 测试的更多信息
testing, we refer you to these
建议大家参阅
docs about when UI testing was
2015 年开始采用 UI 测试时
introduced in 2015.
的相关文档
To enable UI testing with Siri,
为了对 Siri 进行 UI 测试
the main API that is new to iOS
iOS 11 主要新增的一个 API
11 is a way to refer to the Siri
就是在设备上引用
service on the device.
Siri 服务的一种方式
Using this reference, you can
采取这个引用 你可以
feed in Siri request strings
直接使用代码
directly into the Siri service
把 Siri 请求字符串输入到
in code.
Siri 服务中
And because this is done in
此外 因为这是用代码完成的
code, you no longer need to do a
所以你不必再去
manual test of your Siri
手动测试你的 Siri
integration.
集成
Let us see a demo of this.
我们来演示一下
So, I'll take you back to the
我们再回到
same app that we saw earlier
前面见过的那个 App
where we added an authentication
当时 我们添加了一个解锁汽车时的
prompt while unlocking a car.
授权提示
So, it's the same app where
好 这是同一个 App
there's an image showing the
它有一张图像显示
locked state of the car and
汽车正处于锁定状态
using Siri I'm able to test
利用 Siri 我能够测试出
whether I'm able to lock and
自己能否给汽车加锁和
unlock the car.
解锁
So, if I want to test my Siri
所以 如果我想用这个 App
integration in this app, how
对 Siri 集成进行测试
would I do it as a manual test?
我该如何进行手动测试
I would first launch the app,
首先 我会启动 App
set the state to the state I
把它的状态设置为
expect it to be.
我想要的状态
Let's say I want to test whether
比如说 我想测试
my lock requests are working, so
我的锁定请求是否有效
I would want to start it off in
那么我将从它处于
an unlocked state.
解锁状态时开始
Then I would want to issue a
然后 我将发出一个
request to lock the car.
锁定汽车的请求
So, let's issue that request.
现在 我们来发送该请求
OK. And then I would need to
好了 接着 我需要
verify that the request was
验证这个请求
actually handled successfully.
是否真的被成功处理
And in order to do that, I would
为此  我需要
need to launch the app and check
启动这个 App 并且检查
the state-- visually inspect the
其状态 观看检查
state of the app.
这个 App 的状态
So, it looks like when I asked
所以 看来当我要求
Siri to lock the car, the car
Siri 锁上汽车时
was locked, so the test
汽车便被锁上 因此
succeeds.
测试成功
This was the manual test.
这就是手动测试
How would I automate a test like
那我如何完成一次类似的自动化
this?
测试呢
Using the UI automation API, I
利用 UI 自动化 API
can create a UI tests class in
我可以在我的项目里
my project using-- by adding it
创建一个 UI 测试分类
to my UI testing bundle and
把它添加到我的 UI 测试包
create a test like this.
再创建一个类似的测试
So, a test is basically a
所以测试基本上就是
function with these four steps.
包含这四个步骤的一项功能
First, I need to set up the
首先 我需要建立测试
test, then I need to invoke
然后我需要调用 Siri
Siri, then wait for Siri's
接着等待 Siri 的响应
response, and then confirm that
之后确认
Siri's request actually went
Siri 的请求已经通过
through and that the app
此外这个 App 确实已经
actually handled the request.
处理了该请求
So, let's start by setting up a
好的 我们先动手建立一个
test.
测试
So, in order to set up a test,
那么  为了建立一项测试
I've created a helper method to
我创建了一种辅助方法
set the car lock status to
把汽车的上锁状态
false, that is to unlock the
设置为 False 也就是要解锁
car.
汽车
So, before running the locking
所以 在运行上锁测试之前
test, I'm unlocking the car.
我先要解锁汽车
Now, this helper method is-- I
那么 这个辅助方法就是
configured it by using the UI
我使用 UI 记录机制
recording mechanism, which if
对它进行配置
you refer to the UI testing
如果你查阅 UI 测试框架的演讲
framework talk, then you can
你就会明白
learn how to do the UI recording
该如何进行 UI 记录
for generating the test like
从而生成类似于这样的
this.
测试
Then for invoking Siri, I'm
接下来 为了调用 Siri
going to use the API which I
我要使用先前提到的 API
talked about, the new API.
那个新的 API
So, I'm feeding in the request
我现在要输入请求
lock my car.
给汽车上锁
And then, finally, I'm going
最后我准备
to-- then next I'm going to wait
接下来我就要等待
for Siri's response.
Siri 的响应
In order to wait for Siri's
为了等待 Siri 的响应
response, I'm using this API
我将使用这个名为
called wait and this wait
Wait 的 API 这个 wait 参数
parameter-- this wait method
这个 wait 方法
takes two parameters.
使用两个参数
One is an expectation and the
一个参数是预期
other is a time out.
另一个是超时
The expectation I'm waiting to
我正在等待完成的预期
be fulfilled is a predicate
是一个述语式预期
expectation and I'm using the
此外我正在使用的
predicate which basically sleeps
这个述语  它的睡眠时间基本上
for 5 seconds.
为 5 秒
It's nothing fancy.
这不是在幻想
I think it's enough time for
我觉得对于 Siri 来说
Siri to respond to this request.
5 钞钟应该足够对请求作出响应
So, it waits for 5 seconds and
所以 它将等待 5 秒
I'll wait for that wait for 10
我将为此而等待 10 分钟不
minute-- for 10 seconds.
10 秒
So, that was the waiting for
这是等待 Siri 响应
Siri's response piece.
的部分
Next, I need to confirm that the
接下来 我需要确认
state of the app has actually
这个 App 的状态确实已经
changed.
改变
In order to do that, I have
为此  我已经
tagged one of the UI elements in
给 App 里的一个 UI 元素
my app with an accessibility tag
添加了可访问标签
which I am now using to extract
我正在用它提取
that view and then comparing the
那个视图 然后比较那个视图上的
value of the accessibility label
可访问标签的值
on that view to see whether it
看看它是否和我的
matches what I expect.
预期相匹配
So, now that we've written--
由于我们已经编写
automated the test that we just
已经把刚才手动完成的测试
saw manually done, let us run
进行自动化 所以我们就来运行
this automated test and see if
这个自动化测试 看看它是否
it does what we expect.
按照我们的预期运行
Because this is an automated
因为这是一个自动化测试
test, it frees me up to do real
所以它让我有时间去做
development work and not spend
真正的研发工作 而不用
my time testing something which
花费时间测试那些
I already know how it's supposed
我已经知道它将会如何运行的
to work.
事项
So, you notice that it's waiting
因此 你们可以看到这是一个
for Siri's response for 5
需要 Siri 用 5 秒钟响应的等待
seconds and then, finally, it
到了最后  它终于
launches the app and checks
启动这个 App 并且检查
whether the state matches what
当前状态是否与预期
it expects.
相一致
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
And these indicators of
这些欢乐的指示符
happiness tell me that the test
告诉我这项测试
has actually passed.
已经成功
Now, Siri is supported in many
目前 Siri 可支持多种语言
languages and I am most
而我用起来最顺手的
comfortable in English, but I
还是英语 但我可能
might want to test my app's Siri
也想用汉语普通话来测试 App 的
integration in Mandarin.
Siri 集成
Now, I don't speak Mandarin, but
我不会说汉语普通话
I can look up the utterances for
但我可以在开发者网址上
this intent on the developer
查找一些用于编写这个 intent 的
website.
语句表达形式
So, the intent I'm looking for
好 我要找的 intent 是
is INSetCarLockStatusIntent.
INSetCarLockStatusIntent
And in the documentation for
在这个 intent 的文稿纪录里
this intent we actually have
我们实际上有各种语言的
examples of sample utterances in
样本语句
all the languages that Siri
Siri 对这些语言
supports.
全都支持
So, I am going to take the
所以 我将采用一段
example utterance for Mandarin
汉语普通话示例话语
and feed it in here.
将它输入到这里
And I'm going to run this test
然后 我将运行这个测试
on a device which is configured
测试对象是一台配置为汉语普通话语言环境下
to use Siri in Mandarin.
使用 Siri 的设备
So, let me first bring up that
好 我们首先开启
device.
这台设备
So, it launches the app, sets
看 它启动 App
the initial state, invokes Siri,
设置初始状态 调用 Siri
gives it the request, waits for
向它发出请求 等待它的
a response.
响应
And then it launches the app
接着 它再次启动 App
again and confirms that the
确认该状态
state matches what it expects.
与预期相一致
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Again, happiness.
又是欢乐的指示符
Yay!
耶
So, it was that simple to
可以看出
automate my SiriKit integration
自动化 SiriKit 集成测试
testing.
就是这么简单
So, let's recap what we heard
那么 我们来扼要复述一下
today.
今天的讲解内容
From my colleague Angel, we
大家从我的同事 Angel 那里
learned how to handle situations
学习到了如何处理以下各种情况
where users need to be prompted
如果出现
about disambiguating between
联系人重名  或者是
contacts with the same name or
特定联系人拥有
between handles of the-- of a
多个联系方式时  需要提醒用户
particular contact.
消除歧义
We then saw some ways to
接下来 我们讲解了一些
reauthorize Siri requests using
使用本机授权 API 来
the local authentication API.
重新授权 Siri 请求的方法
Then we saw how we can teach
然后 我们知道了如何把
Siri words which are specific to
一些用户特有  或 App 特有的
users or specific to apps, and
词汇教给 Siri
then, finally, we saw some demos
最后 我们还演示了
of how we can do UI testing of
如何对 SiriKit 集成
our SiriKit integration even in
进行 UI 测试
languages that we are not
测试时甚至可以使用我们
conversant in.
不会说的语言
For more information about the
如果想要更多地了解
sample codes and the APIs that
我们在此次演讲中提到的
we talked about in this talk,
示例代码和 API 信息
please refer to this URL.
请参考这个 URL
And we have some other talks
我们还有其他一些演讲
which are relevant to your
它们都与各位的
SiriKit integration, including
SiriKit 集成相关 包括
Apple Pay and CarPlay talks and
Apple Pay 和 CarPlay 的演讲
the talks from previous years
以及前几年的演讲
which we referred to in this
我们在本次演讲中提到的那些内容
talk are listed here.
都已罗列在这个网址
Thank you for coming and we hope
感谢大家的到来 我们希望
you have enough information to
本次演讲之后
create great SiriKit experiences
各位能够凭借充足的信息来
after this talk.
创造强大的 SiriKit 体验
Thank you everybody.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[掌声]